Rush family papers LCP.Rush
Library Company of Philadelphia
- Series I. Benjamin Rush papers
  - Subseries I: Correspondence
    - C. Unbound Correspondence (arranged alphabetically), [Yi2 7402, Yi2 7403, Yi2 7404, and Yi2 7406]
      - Swanwick, J. regarding his right to vote at the election of trustees of the Academy of the Protestant Episcopal Church, 1785 April 12 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Stiles, Ezra to a Jewish Rabbi, 1814 April 28 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      - Stockton, Richard, 1799 November 23 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Taylor, George, letters regarding his voyage to America, letters from Granville Sharp, etc., Charleston, South Carolina, 1784 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Thiebaut, Arsenne (in French), 1806 January 1806 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - University of Pennsylvania regarding appointment of Rush as professor of Chemistry, 1783 November 22 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Valentine, L., 1808 July 4 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - White, Campbell P., 1812 May 28 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Wilck, Joannes Carolus regarding the Academia Regia Scientarium Stockholmensis, 1794-1795 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Willard, Joseph and E. Pearson regarding the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1789 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - William, B. regarding a bequest to the Pennsylvania Society for Promoting the Abolition of Slavery, 1809 December 4 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Subseries II. Property and land records (arranged chronologically)
    - White, Henry (deed), 1789 February 1789 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Cross, James (deed), 1789 February 5 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - White, Samuel (deed), 1789 February 5 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Crooks, Peter (deed), 1789 February 6 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Keble, John (deed), 1789 February 6 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Harper, Joseph (deeds), 1789 March 31 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Scott, James (deed), 1789 March 31 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Byrne, Patrick (deed), 1789 April 16 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Byrne, James (deed), 1789 April 16 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Moylan, John (deed), 1789 May 18 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Claypoole, A. CT. (deed), 1789 December 18 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Stall, John (deed poll), 1792 May 25 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Woodhouse, James (deed poll), 1792 May 25 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Otto, John C. (deed poll), 1793 March 25 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Alston, John (deed poll), 1793 March 25 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Walbridge, Adolphus (deed), 1793 April 29 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Mease, James (deed poll), 1793 August 27 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Deeds to land in Northumberland County, 1794 March 10-15 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Johnston, Francis (certificate of payment for land in Northumberland County), 1794 March (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Simpson, J. (receipt), 1794 March 28 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Hurley, Charles (deed poll), 1794 July 2 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Cooper, Thomas (property history and statement to be made to the board of property about land in Northumberland County taken up by Benjamin Rush), after 1794 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Mifflin, Thomas (patents for lands in Bedford County deeded to Benjamin Rush), 1795 February 7 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Warren, John and Bird (survey), 1797 October 5 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Cummings, John (deeds), 1799 September 7 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Sales of land, 1803 September 1 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Receiver General's Office (receipt), 1804 July 11 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Rush, Benjamin (mortgage), 1912 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Rush, Benjamin (bonds), undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Old Town of Northumberland, undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Subseries III. Financial Records, [Yi2 7271]
    - A. Daybooks, Journals and Ledgers regarding Medical Practice
      - Daybook, 1772-1775 (Volume 46)
      - Daybook, 1775-1779 (Volume 47)
      - Daybook, 1781-1782 (Volume 48)
      - Daybook, 1782-1783 (Volume 49)
      - Daybook, 1783-1785 (Volume 50)
      - Daybook, 1790-1791 (Volume 51)
      - Daybook, 1791-1792 (Volume 52)
      - Daybook, 1793-1795 (Volume 53)
      - Daybook, 1795-1796 (Volume 54)
      - Journal A, 1769-1774 (Volume 55)
      - Journal AA, 1774-1779 (Volume 56)
      - Journal B, 1779-1781 (Volume 57)
      - Journal C, 1781-1784 (Volume 58)
      - Journal D, 1784-1791 (Volume 59)
      - Journal E, 1791-1795 (Volume 60)
      - Journal F, 1795-1799 (Volume 61)
      - Journal G, 1799-1809 (Volume 62)
      - Journal H, 1809-1815 (Volume 63)
      - Ledger A, 1769-1883 (Volume 64)
      - Ledger B, 1779-1783 (Volume 65)
      - Ledger C, 1783-1795 (Volume 66)
      - Ledger D, 1795-1805 (Volume 67)
      - Ledger E, 1806-1814 (Volume 68)
      - Index to Ledgers A-C, Alphabetical list of patients, circa 1769-1795 (Volume 69-70)
      - Index to Ledgers A-D, Alphabetical list of patients of Drs. Rush and Hall, circa 1769-1795 (Volume 71)
    - B. Receipt, account, bank books and estate records
      - Receipt Book D, 1784-1791 (shelved as v. 59); [Yi2 7271] (Volume 72)
      - Family and private account book, 1781-1801; [Yi2 7270 2] (Volume 73)
      - Accounts, 1794-1799; [Yi2 63853 D] (Volume 74)
      - Accounts, 1799-1803; [Yi2 63853 D] (Volume 75)
      - Bank book, 1799-1807; [Yi2 7272 2] (Volume 76)
      - Receipt book, 1807-1828; [Yi2 7272 1] (Volume 77)
      - Cash book of the estate of Benjamin Rush, 1813; [Yi2 7272 3] (Volume 78)
      - Distribution of Dr. Benjamin Rush's property, 1849 March 3 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Subseries IV. Notes, Thoughts, Letters, Diplomas, and Certificates of Benjamin Rush
    - Notes on Various Subjects, 1770-1803; [Yi2 7268] (Volume 79)
    - Notes of Speeches delivered in Convention 1776, in Congress 1776 and in Convention of Pennsylvania, 1776, [Yi2 7400 F 33] (Volume 312)
    - Notes on Continental Congress, etc., 1777-1780; [Yi2 71257 D] (Volume 80)
    - Letters, facts and observations upon a variety of subjects, 1777-1812; [Yi2 7262 v.4] (Volume 81)
    - Letters and thoughts, 1784-1800; [Yi2 7262 F v.1] (Volume 82)
    - Commonplace book, undated; [Yi2 7262 F. v.3] (Volume 83)
    - Addresses on education (first part missing, includes a photocopy following the original), undated; [7400 F 34] (Volume 313)
    - Diplomas and certificates, undated (Box 16)
  - Subseries V. Medical Research and Notes
    - Quack recipe book, 1780-1812; [Yi2 7262 vol. 2] (Volume 84)
    - Medical notes, 1789-1793; [Yi2 7263 #2] (Volume 85)
    - Medical notes, 1803-1804; [Yi2 7264] (Volume 86)
    - Medical Notes, 1804-1809; [Yi2 7265] (Volume 87)
    - Accounts of Epidemic Diseases and Chronic Diseases, volume 1, 1779-1789; [Yi2/7263 #1] (Volume 88)
    - An account of Epidemic Diseases with some chronic diseases added, volume 3, 1793-1794; [Yi2/7263 #3] (Volume 89)
    - An account of Epidemic Diseases with some chronic diseases added, volume 4, 1794-1798; [Yi2/7263 #4] (Volume 90)
    - An account of Epidemic Diseases with some chronic diseases added, volume 5, 1799-1813; [Yi2/7263 #5] (Volume 91)
    - Histories of the Manner of Life of Sundry Men and Women Above 80 Years of Life, 1789; [Yi2 7267] (Volume 91.5)
  - Subseries VI. Writings by Dr. Benjamin Rush, [Yi2/7273]
    - "The Espousals of Plants or a Compendium of the Sexual or Linnean System of Botany", undated; [Yi2 7273] (Volume 92)
    - Lectures on the Institutes of Physic by William Cullen, M.D., Professor of Medicine in the University of Edinburgh, volumes 1-3, 1767-1768; [Yi2 7274 9-11] (Volume 93-95)
    - Lectures upon Chemistry by William Cullen, M.D., undated; [Y12 7274 1-3] (Volume 96-98)
    - Lectures on the Practice of Physic by William Cullen, M.D., Professor of Medicine in the University of Edinburgh (volumes 1 and 2), 1768; [Y12 7274 4-5] (Volume 99-99.5)
    - Clinical Lectures delivered in the Royal Infirmary of Edinburgh in 1768 (volumes 1-2), [Y12 7274 7-8] (Volume 100-101)
    - A Course of Lectures on the Practice of Medicine by William Cullen, Professor of Medicine in the University of Edinburgh (volumes 1, 3 and 4), 1769; [Y12 7274 6] (Volume 102-104)
    - Notes from A Course of Lectures on the Practice of Medicine, circa 1769; [Yi2 7274 6] (Volume 105)
    - "Work on Hygiene", 1813; [7395 F 10] (Volume 135)
    - Autobiography, pages 367-383 (regarding religion and domestic events), undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Diary of Nehemiah, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Subseries VII. Professorship at University of Pennsylvania
    - A. Lists of Students
      - 1788-1803, 1804-1813, [Yi2 7270 1] (Volume 106)
      - 1813-1814, [Yi2 7270 2] (Volume 107)
    - B. Lectures, Yi2 7394; Yi2 7395; Yi2 7396; Yi2 7397; Yi2 7398; Yi2 7399; Yi2 7400]
      - On Natural Philosophy for the Young Ladies Academy: The Application of the Principles of Natural Philosophy, Chemistry, and Medicine to Domestic and Culinary Purposes, composed for the use of the Young Ladies' Academy in Philadelphia, 1787 October; [7395 F 11, 7395 F 12, 7395 F 13, 7395 F 14] (Volume 108)
      - Notes of Lectures on the Practice of Physic in the University of Pennsylvania, 1788-1789; [7400 F 33] (Volume 109)
      - On the Practice of Medicine, undated; [7394 F 1] (Volume 110)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Of inflammatory fevers, of typhus and mitior and the Plague, undated; [7394 F 2] (Volume 111)
      - On the Practice of Medicine, undated; [7394 F 3] (Volume 112)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Of prognosis in fevers critical days, pneumara vera, pneumary motha, pneumary typhodes, and catarrh or influenza, undated; [7394 F 4] (Volume 113)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Angina, rheumatism, phthisis pulmonatis, small pox and inoculation, undated; [7394 F 5] (Volume 114)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: The measles, angina maligna, scarlatina, chicken pox, ensipias (?), military fever, phrenetis, and hepatitis, undated; [7394 F 6] (Volume 115)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Gastritis, enteritis, splenitis (?), nephritis, cystitis, otalgia or earache, hemorrhoids, opthalmia, phlogasis, gangrene, sphacelus, panonychia (?), anthrax, burns and frozen, hemorrhages, hemoptysis, epitasis, homatymensis, and gout, undated; [7394 F 7] (Volume 116)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Gout, rheumitalgia, tooth ache, arthropnosis, and apoplexy, undated; [7394 F 8] (Volume 117)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Apoplexy, catalepsy, palsy and coma, waterfullness ?, spasms, tetanus, hydrophobia, convulsions, chorea, epilepsy, and hysteria, undated; [7394 F 9] (Volume 118)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Chorea, asthma, dyspmea ?, angina pectoris, puterpis(?), pysosis, colic, diarrhea, palpitatis, singultis, and dyspepsia, undated; [7394 F 10] (Volume 119)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Hypocondriasis, versanie(?) or diseases of the mind, and mania, undated; [7394 F 11] (Volume 120)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Remedies for Atonic (?), madness, weakness and defect of memory, fatuity (?), and diseases of the passions, undated; [7394 F 12] (Volume 121)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Of the passions generally, love, grief, anger, fear, joy and lust, undated; [7394 F 13] (Volume 122)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Syncope, asphyxia, cachexia, tubes, polysania (?), hectic fever, typany, dropsy, anasarca, ascites, hydrothorax, hydrocephalus, hydrocele, physcoma, rickets, scrophula, elephantiasis, trichoma-jaterus (?), and scurvy., undated; [7394 F 14] (Volume 123)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Of local diseases, head ache, gulta serina and deafness, costiveness, ischuria, cancer, cutaneous diseases, and old age, undated; [7394 F 15] (Volume 124)
      - On the Practice of Medicine: Diseases of old people, diseases of women, menorrhagia, leucorrhea, cessation of menses, puerperal fever, diseases of children, and diseases of Negroes, undated; [7394 F 16] (Volume 125)
      - Introduction to a course of clinical lectures, 1791-1794; [7395 F 1, 7395 F 2] (Volume 126-127)
      - An inaugural lecture on the necessity of combining theory and practice in medicine, 1791 November 7; [7395 F 3] (Volume 128)
      - Therapeuticks [sic], undated; [7395 F 4, 7395 F 5] (Volume 129-130)
      - Therapeuticks [sic], 1814-1817; [7395 F 6, 7395 F 7] (Volume 131-132)
      - Upon the principles of materia medica, undated; [7395 F 8, 7395 F 9] (Volume 133-134)
      - Notes from lectures, undated; [7395 F 15] (Volume 136)
      - On pathology: series 1: On the uses of diseases, definition of disease, and cause of disease, undated; [7396 F 1] (Volume 137)
      - On pathology: series 1: On the proximate cause of disease, on debility, on predisposition, and native and acquired, undated; [7396 F 2] (Volume 138)
      - On pathology: series 1: Old and copied lectures on pathology, undated; [7396 F 3] (Volume 139)
      - On pathology: series 1: Forms of disease continued, and the application of the doctrine of the unity of disease, undated; [7396 F 4] (Volume 140)
      - On pathology: series 1: On the effects and sorts of disease continued, undated; [7396 F 5] (Volume 141)
      - On pathology: series 1: Division of diseases, undated; [7396 F 6] (Volume 142)
      - On pathology: series 1: On the sensible qualities in the air, of the effects of heat, and of the effects of cold, undated; [7396 F 7] (Volume 143)
      - On pathology: series 1: On the sensible qualities in the air, and of the effects of cold, continued, undated; [7396 F 8] (Volume 144)
      - On pathology: series 1, undated; [7396 F 9] (Volume 145)
      - On pathology: series 1: On the effects of winds, and on the relative influence of seasons and months upon human life, undated; [7396 F 10] (Volume 146)
      - On pathology: series 1: On the remote causes of disease from insensible matters in the air, undated; [7396 F 11] (Volume 147)
      - On pathology: series 1: On the remote causes of disease from insensible matters in the air, continued, undated; [7396 F 12] (Volume 148)
      - On pathology: series 1: On miasmatic fevers, continued, undated; [7396 F 13] (Volume 149)
      - On pathology: series 1: On the laws of epidemics, undated; [7396 F 14] (Volume 150)
      - On pathology: series 1: On the influence of situations, houses, change in situation, thunder and lightning, earthquakes, sound, and of the heavenly bodies, undated; [7396 F 15] (Volume 151)
      - On pathology: series 2, undated; [7396 F 16] (Volume 152)
      - On pathology: series 3: Use of diseases, undated; [7396 F 17] (Volume 153)
      - On pathology: series 3: Morbid effects of cold, of purity and density of the air, and of impregnations and mixtures of the air, undated; [7396 F 18] (Volume 154)
      - On pathology: series 3, undated; [7396 F 19] (Volume 155)
      - On pathology: series 3: Situations continued, aliments, fish, land animals and vegetable aliment, undated; [7396 F 20] (Volume 156)
      - On pathology: series 3: Ways of preparing aliment, effects of condiments, effects of coffee, and effects of drinks, undated; [7396 F 21] (Volume 157)
      - On pathology: series 3: Diseases from too much motion, sleep or wakefulness, undue exercise of the faculties, of love, of joy, of anger, of grief, of fear, of ambition, of avarice of ven. [venereal] appetite, from situations, from government and from religions, undated; [7396 F 22] (Volume 158)
      - On pathology: series 3: Diseases from employments, from amusements, from peculiar customs, and from unhealthy ancestors, undated; [7396 F 23] (Volume 159)
      - On pathology: series 3: Diseases of puberty continued, of adolescency, and of old age, undated; [7396 F 24] (Volume 160)
      - On pathology: series 3: Of local diseases, of the black color of the Africans, and of the proximate cause of death, undated; [7396 F 25] (Volume 161)
      - On pathology: series 3: On the signs of diseases, undated; [7396 F 26] (Volume 162)
      - Medical notes, undated; [7396 F 27] (Volume 163)
      - On physiology: Of animal life, of external and internal stimuli, undated; [7397 F 1] (Volume 164)
      - On physiology: Of animal life in sleep in different ages [in the fetus in utero; in infancy; in childhood; in youth; in middle life; in old age; in persons born deaf, dumb and blind; in idiots; and in person who fast long], undated; [7397 F 2] (Volume 165)
      - On physiology: Of animal life in drowning and freezing, in different nations among Indians, of the inhabitants of hot countries, cold countries, Eastern countries, and free countries, of the poor everywhere, of mental stimuli, love of money, and love of fame, of different religions, of animal life in other animals, and of animal heat, undated; [7397 F 3] (Volume 166)
      - On physiology: Of animal heat, continued and of respiration, coughing, sneezing, yawning, laughter, crying and voice and speech, undated; [7397 F 4] (Volume 167)
      - On physiology: Voice, continued, and circulation of the blood, undated; [7397 F 5] (Volume 168)
      - On physiology, undated; [7397 F 6] (Volume 169)
      - Sleep and dreams, undated; [7397 F 7, 7397 F 8, 7397 F 9] (Volume 170-172)
      - On physiology: Touch, undated; [7397 F 10] (Volume 173)
      - On physiology: Of seeing, undated; [7397 F 11] (Volume 174)
      - On physiology: Of hearing, undated; [7397 F 12] (Volume 175)
      - On physiology: Of hearing, continued, undated; [7397 F 13] (Volume 176)
      - On physiology: Dreams, aliment and hunger, undated; [7397 F 14] (Volume 177)
      - On physiology: Of digestion, of the Chyle, and of the blood, undated; [7397 F 15] (Volume 178)
      - On physiology: Lymphatics, secretions, and nutrition, undated; [7397 F 16] (Volume 179)
      - On physiology: Nutrition continued, female constitution, female mind, catamenia, male constitution, and venereal appetite, undated; [7397 F 17] (Volume 180)
      - On physiology: Venereal appetite continued, generation and conception, and parturition, undated; [7397 F 18] (Volume 181)
      - Recapitulation of lectures upon animal life, undated; [7397 F 19] (Volume 182)
      - Lecture on animal heat, undated; [7397 F 20] (Volume 183)
      - Animal Heat (two books), undated; [7406 F 42] (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - On fevers: On the different states of fever, undated; [7398 F 1, 7398 F 2] (Volume 184-185)
      - On fevers: The cure of fever, undated; [7398 F 3] (Volume 186)
      - On fevers: The cure of fever after bloodletting, evacuents, and remedies for redressing morbid excitement, undated; [7398 F 4] (Volume 187)
      - On fevers: The cure of fever, undated; [7398 F 5, 7398 F 6, 7398 F 7, 7398 F 8] (Volume 188-191)
      - On fevers: Prognosis of fevers, undated; [7398 F 9, 7398 F 10] (Volume 192-193)
      - On fevers: On critical days, undated; [7398 F 11] (Volume 194)
      - On fevers: Mild bilious fever, inflam bilious fever, yellow fever, and the plague, undated; [7398 F 12] (Volume 195)
      - On fevers: Prophylaxis of yellow fever and plague, 1802 January 18; [7398 F 13] (Volume 196)
      - On fevers: Hectic fever, undated; [7398 F 14] (Volume 197)
      - On fevers: Jail, ship, or hospital fever, undated; [7398 F 15] (Volume 198)
      - On fevers: Jail, ship, or hospital fever, fever from opium, and fever from mercury, undated; [7398 F 16] (Volume 199)
      - On fevers: From the bite of rabid animals, undated; [7398 F 17] (Volume 200)
      - On fevers: From poisons, undated; [7398 F 18] (Volume 201)
      - On fevers: Sweating, fainting, burning, cold and chilly, and petechial states of fever, undated; [7398 F 19] (Volume 202)
      - On fevers: Intestinal states of fever, undated; [7398 F 20] (Volume 203)
      - On fevers: Symptoms and remedies, undated; [7398 F 21] (Volume 204)
      - On fevers: Pulmonary state of fever, undated; [7398 F 22] (Volume 205)
      - On fevers: [Pneumonary fevers], undated; [7398 F 23] (Volume 206)
      - On fevers: Pulmonary consumption, undated; [7398 F 24, 7398 F 25, 7398 F 26, 7398 F 27] (Volume 207-210)
      - On fevers: Diseases of the lungs, undated; [7398 F 28] (Volume 211)
      - On fevers: Emptive states of fever (smallpox, vaccination sound, measles, Erisepelas, military fever (?), chicken pox, Pern (?), and essere), undated; [7398 F 29] (Volume 212)
      - On fevers: Anginora states of fever (enaligna (?), scarlatina anginora, suffocativa, trachiatis, mumps, phaningca, and angina tonsillaris), undated; [7398 F 30] (Volume 213)
      - On fevers: Anginora states of fever (mumps, [ulcerous and malignant] throat, scarlatina, angina suffocativa, and angina trachiatis), undated; [7398 F 31] (Volume 214)
      - On fevers: Tic doloroux, undated; [7398 F 32, 7398 F 33] (Volume 215-216)
      - On fevers: Hemorrhagic states of fever, undated; [7398 F 34] (Volume 217)
      - On fevers: Gastrics and intestic states of fever, undated; [7398 F 35] (Volume 218)
      - On fevers: Heptatic diseases and disorders, undated; [7398 F 36, 7398 F 37, 7398 F 38, 7398 F 39, 7398 F 40, 7398 F 41 ] (Volume 219-224)
      - On fevers: Amenorhagic state of fever, undated; [7398 F 42] (Volume 225)
      - On fevers: Hemorrhoidal state of fever, undated; [7398 F 43] (Volume 226)
      - On fevers: Diseases and disorders of the urinary organs, undated; [7398 F 44, 7398 F 45, 7398 F 46] (Volume 227-229)
      - On fevers: Ophthalmic state of fever, undated; [7399 F 1, 7399 F 2] (Volume 230-231)
      - On fevers: Odontalgic state of fever or diseases of the teeth, undated; [7399 F 3] (Volume 232)
      - On fevers: Otalgic state of fever, undated; [7399 F 4] (Volume 233)
      - On fevers: States of fever (otalgic, apthous, scrophulous, scorbutic, convulsive, hysterical and hypocondrical, and cutaneous), undated; [7399 F 5] (Volume 234)
      - On fevers: States of fever (cutaneous), undated; [7399 F 6] (Volume 235)
      - On fevers: States of fever (scorbutic, hydrophobic, convulsive, hysterical or hypocondirical, and cutaneous), undated; [7399 F 7] (Volume 236)
      - On fevers: Hydropsic states of fever, undated; [7399 F 8] (Volume 237)
      - On fevers: States of fever, undated; [7399 F 9] (Volume 238)
      - On fevers: Of the cephalic states of fever, undated; [7399 F 10] (Volume 239)
      - On fevers: States of fever, undated; [7399 F 11] (Volume 240)
      - On fevers: Introduction of lectures upon apoplexy, palsy, coma and epilepsy, 1811 February 15; [7399 F 12] (Volume 241)
      - On fevers: Diseases of the heart, blood vessels, also of the brain and nerves, undated; [7399 F 13, 7399 F 14] (Volume 242-243)
      - On fevers: Diseases of the blood vessels and nerves, of apoplexy and the means of preventing it, undated; [7399 F 15] (Volume 244)
      - On fevers: Of apoplexy and coma, undated; [7399 F 16] (Volume 245)
      - On fevers: Palsy, catalepsy, coma, and wakefulness, undated; [7399 F 17] (Volume 246)
      - On fevers: Palsy and catalepsy, undated; [7399 F 18] (Volume 247)
      - On fevers: Wakefulness, undated; [7399 F 19] (Volume 248)
      - On fevers: On vertigo, undated; [7399 F 20] (Volume 249)
      - On fevers: Vertigo and head ache, undated; [7399 F 21] (Volume 250)
      - On fevers: Head ache, undated; [7399 F 22] (Volume 251)
      - On fevers: Epilepsy, undated; [7399 F 23] (Volume 252)
      - On fevers: On convulsions and epilepsy, undated; [7399 F 24] (Volume 253)
      - On fevers: Costiveness, undated; [7399 F 25, 7399 F 26] (Volume 254-255)
      - On fevers: On hysteria, undated; [7399 F 27, 7399 F 28] (Volume 256-257)
      - On fevers: Dyspepsia, undated; [7399 F 29, 7399 F 30, 7399 F 31] (Volume 258-260)
      - On fevers: Dyspnea, angina pectoris, hooping cough, and tremors, undated; [7399 F 32] (Volume 261)
      - On fevers: On syncope, and suspended animation, undated; [7399 F 33] (Volume 262)
      - On fevers: On the asthma, undated; [7399 F 34, 7399 F 35] (Volume 263-264)
      - On fevers: Debility, "Of the origin of evil or every kind", undated; [7399 F 36] (Volume 265)
      - On fevers: On syncope, asphyxia, and trance, undated; [7399 F 37] (Volume 266)